Guide to the Edmund Blunden Letters and Manuscripts,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Edmund Blunden Letters and Manuscripts,
1922-1968
Blunden, Edmund, 1896-1974.
104 items (1 box).
Columbia University Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Butler Library, New York, NY 10027.
4078390
Biographical Note
English poet, Edmund Charles Blunden.
Scope and Content
Letters and manuscripts, including correspondence with his publisher, Richard Cobden-Sanderson, and Pauline Francis Stephens, Dorothy Hewlett Kilgour, Norman Kilgour, and Cyril W. Beaumont. The collection also includes the copy of Blunden's "Undertones of War" (London, Cobden-Sanderson, 1928), inscribed to Richard Cobden-Sanderson with a poem, dated 27 July 1929, and containing Blunden's notes, corrections and illustrations throughout.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 3 series:
Series I: Cataloged Series
Series II: Arranged Series
Series III: Artwork
Subjects
Cobden-Sanderson, Richard.; Stephens, Pauline Francis.; Hewlett, Dorothy.; Kilgour, Norman.; Beaumont, Cyril W. (Cyril William), 1891-1976.; English poetry--20th century.; Poets, English
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located on-site.
Acquisition
1973 Letters and manuscripts Friends of the Columbia Libraries Gift
Related Material
Blunden's copy of "Undertones of War" is cataloged for the Rare Book collection.
- Series I: Cataloged Series
  - Subseries I.1: Correspondence
    - Abbott, Claude Colleer (Box 1)
    - Andrade, Edward Neville da Costa
    - Abse, Dannie
    - Arlott, John
    - Bateson, Frederick Wilse
    - Beaumont, Cyril W.
    - Bell, Adrian Hanbury
    - Betjeman, John
    - Blunden, Edmund
    - Blunden, G. A.
    - Brett-Smith
    - Bone, Muirhead (Box 2)
    - Bottrall, Francis James Ronald Bottomley, Gordon
    - Cary, Joyce
    - Cecil, Lord David
    - Church, Richard
    - Clemens, Cyril
    - Cobden-Sanderson, Richard
    - Day-Lewis, Cecil
    - de la Mare, Walter
    - Desborough, Lady Ethel
    - Dobree, Bonamy
    - Doolittle, Hilda (H.D.)
    - Engle, Paul & Baldwin Maswell
    - Garrod, Heathcote William
    - Grant, Douglas
    - Green, Roger
    - Greene, Graham
    - Hall, John
    - Hamilton, Sir George Rostrevor
    - Heath-Stubbs, John
    - Jeffares, A. Norman
    - Keynes, Geoffrey
    - Knight, George Wilson
    - Lowndes, Marie Belloc
    - Lucas, Edward Verrall
    - Mac Donald, Hugh
    - Morgan, Charles Langbridge
    - Morley, Frank
    - Murray, David Leslie
    - Napier, Charles
    - Nichols, Robert
    - Orwell, George
    - Pinto, Vivian de Sola
    - Plomer, William
    - Raine, Kathleen
    - Rickword, Edgell
    - Rothenstein, Sir William
    - Rowse, Alfred Leslie
    - Sassoon, Siegfried
    - Sherriff, Robert Cedric
    - Sparrow, John
    - Spender, Stephen
    - Squire, J.C.
    - Stead, William Force
    - Strong, Leonard Alfred George
    - Temple, William [ A. B. of Canterbury]
    - Turner, Walter James Redfern
    - Wallop, Gerard Vernon
    - Williamson, Henry
    - Woolf, Leonard Sidney
    - Blunden, Edmund To Aki Hayashi, 1924-1931 (Box 3)
    - Blunden, Edmund To Aki Hayashi, 1932-1934 (Box 4)
    - Blunden, Edmund To Aki Hayashi, 1935-1940 (Box 5)
    - Blunden, Edmund To Aki Hayashi, 1941-1951 (Box 6)
    - Blunden, Edmund To Aki Hayashi, 1952 -1962 (Box 7)
    - Blunden, Edmund To Sylva Norman, 8 Oct. 1930-28 June 1932 (Box 8)
    - Blunden, Edmund To Sylva Norman, 1 July 1932-28 Feb. 193[3?] (Box 9)
    - Blunden, Edmund To Sylva Norman, 1 March 1933- 31 Dec.1937 (Box 10)
    - Blunden, Edmund To Sylva Norman, 1938-42 (Box 11)
    - Blunden, Edmund To Sylva Norman, 1943-44 (Box 12)
    - Blunden, Edmund To Sylva Norman, 1945-49 (Box 13)
    - Blunden, Edmund To Sylva Norman, 1950-56 (Box 14)
    - Blunden, Edmund To Sylva Norman, 1957-62 (Box 15)
    - Blunden, Edmund To Sylva Norman, 1963-70 (Box 16)
  - Subseries I.2: Manuscripts
    - Blunden, Edmund (Box 17)
    - Blunden, Edmund Diaries and notebooks (Box 17a)
  - Subseries I.3: Photographs
    - The Anchorage Inn, Yaldiing &..... (Box 17)
    - Blunden, Edmund
    - Hardy, Thomas and Canon Pentin
- Series II: Arranged Series
  - Subseries II.1: Correspondence
    - A., Isabel (Box 18)
    - Alastair
    - Allen, G.K.
    - Allen, Tom J.
    - Altick, Richard D.
    - Anday, W.S.
    - Arthur
    - Ash, Kathleen
    - Atkinsin, J.
    - Atkinson, R.L.
    - Atthill, Robin
    - B.
    - B., A. H.
    - B., B.
    - B., I.
    - Bailey, J.T.
    - Ball, Arthur
    - Barker, D.A.
    - Barrow, W.M.
    - Beachcroft, T.O.
    - Bebbington, W.G.
    - Bell, Douglas
    - Bell, Eric S.
    - Bell, Fanny
    - Bell, Ivan
    - Benjamin, Lewis S.
    - Bentley, F.H.
    - Bernstein, Hans
    - Bicknell, E.G.
    - Bicknell, John P.C.
    - Billingham, J.S.
    - Binding, Rudolf G.
    - Bishop, M.
    - Bismingle, M.J.
    - Black, M.H.
    - Blacket, Geoffrey
    - Blanchy, Norman
    - Blunden, Claire
    - Blunden, G. M.
    - Blunden, Mary Daines
    - Bokhari, Z.A.
    - Boulton, Marjorie
    - Boyd, James
    - Bozman, E.F.
    - Brander, Laurence
    - Brewer, Luther
    - Brown, Margaret
    - Browne..., H. C.
    - Brumbough,Thomas
    - Buck, Hector
    - Buckley Huguans, F.
    - Bullough, Geoffrey
    - Buxton, Marjorie
    - Byrne, E.
    - C., George
    - Campbell, Gerard
    - Cape Jonathan
    - Capiz, Ellen
    - Careterar, William
    - Carlson,? Jim
    - Cartiwright
    - Cassels, James
    - Chadwick, A.E.
    - Chambers, Olive
    - Chapman, J.B.
    - Chapman, John
    - Chatto and Windus
    - Cheetle, H.F.
    - Christ
    - Clyde Christie, L.
    - Clark, G.A.
    - Clarke, A.G.
    - Cleafe, R.
    - Colin
    - Colles, Hester
    - Collins, A.F.W.
    - Conrad Senet, R.
    - Cosham, A.J.
    - Collins, W.A.R.
    - Coulter, John W.
    - Craster, H.H.R.
    - Creswick, H.R.
    - Crow, John W.
    - Crowsley, Ernest G.
    - Currie, G.A.
    - D., Kaethe
    - Daines, P.
    - Datt, T.
    - Davies, Mary W. (Box 18 (cont.))
    - Davison, R.W
    - de Candolle, Beatrice
    - Delatte, F.
    - de la Mare, Richard
    - de Lyons-Pike, C.R.
    - de Trafford, G.E.
    - de Trafford, W.P.C.
    - Dilnot, George
    - Dixon, John K.S.
    - Doddle, Polydor
    - Dolding, K.
    - Doubleday, Dorand and
    - Company
    - Douglas, Mary Jo
    - Downing, F.A.
    - Dudley Ward, Dorothy
    - Durell, Harry T.
    - E., John
    - Ede, Elton
    - Edwards, A.C.
    - Edwards, Harry
    - Elizabeth
    - Ellis, Arthur
    - Ellis-Fermont, Mme.
    - Ellison, Norman F.
    - English Association
    - Eleventh Regiment
    - Esmi
    - Evans, A. Dwye
    - F., Patrick
    - Fabb, C.B.
    - Farrar, John
    - Farrow, Walter
    - Fass, A.H.
    - Fehl, Noah E.
    - Ferling, Keith
    - Finch, Edie J.
    - Fletcher, S.A.
    - Foreman, E.
    - Forman, Maurice B.
    - Foster, T.F.V.
    - Frank, M.H.
    - Freewood, E..
    - Friend, F.W. & M.L.
    - Fryer, Hal
    - Fyfe, W. H.
    - G., G.H.
    - G., Herbert
    - G., H.W.
    - Garner, Arthur
    - Gay, Maurice James
    - George, Eric
    - Glantz, Anna
    - Godfrey, Walter A.
    - Goldsmith, J.
    - Gons, R.C.
    - Grahame, Elspeth
    - Grant, Joan
    - Greacen, Robert
    - Green, Margaret
    - Greene, Hugh Carleton
    - Greenlaw, J.
    - Grey, Ruth
    - Gyde, Arnold
    - Hayashi, Aki
    - H., D.
    - H., L.
    - Haldane Broadcasts
    - Haldane, Charlotte
    - Halsband, Robert
    - Halsor, Laurence
    - Halsey, Lionel
    - Hamish Hamilton Ltd
    - Hams, W.S.
    - Hanskell, Q.
    - Hardie, Alec
    - Harrison, B.
    - Harrison, G.B.
    - Harrison, G.H.
    - Hart, M.M.
    - Hartt-Davis, Rupert
    - Hayashi, Aki
    - Haye, Colvyn
    - Heath, A.
    - Heath, C.L.
    - Henderson, John
    - Hennell, Thomas
    - Henshaw, L.
    - Hensman, Berton
    - Herdman, E.
    - Hine, Reginald
    - Hirst, Frances W.
    - Hogarth Press
    - Hobhouse, Paul
    - Hodgson, A.
    - Holdes, A.
    - Holliwell, W.S.
    - Hon, E.
    - Hosking, J.E.
    - House, H.W.
    - Houtchens, Lawrence H.
    - Howards, C.E.H.
    - Hoyte, W.N.
    - Hubback, Eva M.
    - Huskerish, Patricia
    - Hutchison, G.S.
    - Isaac, I.
    - J., H.
    - James
    - Johnson, R.B.
    - Ju, Peng
    - Kamp, Harold
    - Kathleen
    - Kawakatu, Y.
    - Kelt, J. (Box 18 (cont.))
    - Kendon, Frank
    - Kenning, Bill
    - Kenward, James
    - Kieth, J. Innes
    - King, Edward
    - King, Joyce
    - Kirkpatrick, W.
    - Knapp, R.
    - Knowles, Guy
    - Kubota, M.
    - L., G.
    - L., H.
    - Lamont, L.M.
    - Laselles, Mary
    - Law, Angela
    - Leggett, Thomas
    - Leigh, E.
    - Lemperley, Paul
    - le Pan, Douglas
    - Lepouids, Pierre
    - [Levins], Robert
    - Levine, Isaac
    - Lewis, F.
    - Longman, R.G.
    - Lydall, E.F.
    - Lyttelton, George William
    - M., A.
    - M., J.D.
    - M., T.
    - M., V.
    - MacBride, L.M.
    - Macdonald, R.J.
    - Mackarness, Roger
    - Maclechose, Alexander
    - MacMillan & Co. LTD
    - MacMillan, David
    - Martineau, G.D.
    - Marsh, George L.`
    - Massingham, Anne
    - Matthews, Denise
    - Maud (Blunden's Aunt)
    - Mayo, C.W.
    - Meggitt, C.
    - [Miscellaneous]
    - Milkman, Jerome
    - Minchin, Cotton
    - Moore, H.B.
    - Morgan, A.E.
    - Morgan, J.
    - Morris, W.A.D.
    - Morrison, Hugh
    - "Most appreciative critic"
    - Moult, Tom
    - Murray Brooks, W.L.
    - Myatt, Geoff
    - Myatt, Nellie
    - N., H.S.
    - N., I.
    - Nakajima, Fumio
    - Napier, Hazel
    - Negretti, P.A.
    - Nichols, C.A.
    - Norman, Sylva
    - Nyers, R.E.
    - O., A.
    - Okado, Tetsuzo
    - Olive, N.C.
    - Olley, Arthur E.
    - O'Malley, Jane
    - Orchard, W.
    - Oxford University Press
    - P., P.W.
    - P., R.
    - Page, Fred
    - Parfitt, W.C.
    - Parker, Edward
    - Peck, Walter
    - Penna, R.F.
    - Perring, A.R.M.
    - Percy
    - Perry, P.D.
    - Peters, Augustin Dudley
    - Phill
    - Phillips, Vaughan
    - Pike, E.
    - Pilcher, J.A.
    - Potter, Kenneth
    - Polunin, Nicholas
    - Poskitt, F.R.
    - Powys, Atherton
    - Pratt, Arthur L.
    - Prentice, G.R.
    - Preston, J.H.
    - Price, Irene
    - Price, Ronald J.
    - Price, Victor
    - Prickett, C.W.
    - Priestly, Mary/Mildred Brook
    - Publishers
    - Read, Hudson
    - Read, Sheila
    - Reade, Aleyn Lyell
    - Reed, Dorothy
    - Revells, Herbert
    - Richard
    - Richards, Mrs.
    - Richmond, Sir Bruce
    - Rieu, E.V.
    - Roberts, Walter
    - Robertson, Ian
    - Robertson-Glasgow, R.C.
    - Roger
    - Rogers, Arthur
    - Rollins, B. (Box 18 (cont.))
    - Rose-Innes, Arthur
    - Ross, Philip
    - Rowe-Evans, A.
    - Rye, Anthony
    - S., D.N.
    - Saito, Takeshi
    - Sanday, William
    - Sandford, Egbert
    - Sarabhai, Bharati
    - Sarad, Donald
    - Sato Kyoshi
    - Saws, Y.R.
    - Schollick, H.L.
    - Scott, Daphne
    - Scott, Dorothea
    - Scott, James Rolfe Arnold
    - Sefton, Sam
    - Seymour, William Kean
    - Senet, R. Conrad
    - Shannon, Sheila
    - Shaw, Kennedy
    - Shaw, Lucy W.
    - Simon, Andre
    - Simoy
    - Sisam, Kenneth
    - Slader, W.
    - Slater, F. Carey
    - Smith, Simon Nowell
    - Snell, Reginald Snowdery, J.K.
    - Sone, J.
    - Spencer, Arthur G.
    - Stanley-Jones, E.
    - Sterling, T.S.
    - Stewart, C.W.
    - Stonelay, Herbert/Luce Vicarage
    - Stott, R. Toole
    - Stephenson, John B.
    - Sukuki, Trizo
    - Sutherland, James R.
    - Sutherland, M.S.
    - TM, B.
    - Taketomo, Torao
    - Tambimuttu, M.J.
    - Taylor, F.C.
    - Thomas, J. Hadyn
    - Thompson, Donald
    - Thompson, E.H.
    - Thompson, P. Gilchrist
    - Thompson, W.G.
    - Tibble, Anne
    - Tinney,, Margaret S.
    - Tomlinson, Philip
    - Trechmann, E.
    - Tregsning, E.A.
    - Turner, Barbara C.
    - Turner, C.E.
    - Turell, John
    - Tweed, Blanche Susan
    - University of Hong Kong
    - Uttley, Alison
    - Vetch, H.
    - Vidler, Edith
    - Vincent, M.C.
    - Vines, Sherard
    - W.
    - W., F.
    - W., George
    - W., Henry
    - Waldman, Milton
    - Wan, Lo
    - Ward, A.C.
    - Wardle, Mark
    - Watt, A.S.
    - Watt, Rebecca
    - Webb, K.H.
    - Webster, David L.
    - Welland, Dennis
    - Wells, K.
    - Westbrook, Charles
    - Westall, R.T.
    - Wheeler, Dick
    - White, Graham
    - White, H.J.
    - White, H.O.
    - White, Jimmy
    - Wikinson, Cyril Hackett
    - William-Olsom, H.
    - Williams, Alan M.
    - Williams, May
    - Williams, Stephen
    - Wilson, J.G.
    - Wilson, Mary L.G. Carus
    - Winbolt, S.E.
    - Winchris, H. Colton
    - Wolfe, E. George
    - Wood, Edmund
    - Wood, F. Featherstone
    - Woodair, E.
    - Woodward, Arthur M.
    - Wren Howard, G.
    - Wright, Philip A.
    - Wynne Mason, W.
    - Yamamoto, Susumo
    - Yan, Ann & Kam
    - Yin, Da Tsung
    - Young, N.H.
    - ZZO
  - Subseries II.2: Manuscripts
    - Blunden, Edmund Notes on James Thomson, John Hoole, J., (1 folder, ) (Box 19)
    - Moore, Harriet Shelley Portrait, Shelley
    - Extract from review of the English Heritage series
    - Typed excerpt from "The Tragedy of the Queen of Cornwall and "A Pair of Blue Eyes"
    - Coleridge Copies of 3 letters by Coleridge
    - Clare Blunden C.V.
  - Subseries II.3: Documents
    - Record of payment to Blunden
    - Postal receipt Receipt to Mrs. Blunden
    - Several royalty statements.
    - Printed ephemera
    - Newspaper clippings; circulars Pamphlet, etc., (1 folder, )
- Series III: Artwork
  - Subseries III.1: Letters from Blunden to Sylva Norman in which there are sketches by Blunden
    - 1932; Feb. 27; March 3; 7; 8; 10; 11; 12; 23; 28; 29; April 13; 15; May 8; 15; 31; June 13; 21; 22; July 24; 26; Aug. 26; Oct. 10-11; Nov. 7; 29; 30
    - 1933; Jan. 4; 27; Feb. 19; March 16; 31; April 18; June 3; 20; 23
    - 1936; July 12; Aug. 20
    - 1937; June 29
    - 1939; Aug. 3
    - 1949; Jan. 7
    - 1953; Nov. 8
    - 1954; June 28; Sept. 11
    - 1955; Aug. 11
    - 1956; March 11; April 29
    - 1960; June 12
    - 1961; Jan. 12-16
    - 1964; Dec. 14; March 29; May 4; Aug. 14
    - 1966; Jan. 24